[Orchestra Tuning]
[Tuning Continues]
[Tuning Stops]
[Audience Applauding]
[Classical]
[Audience Cheering, Applauding]
- [Applause, Cheering Stop]
- [Tape Clicks]
[Woman]
Craig, honey, it's time for bed.
Craig, honey, time to get up.
- Lotte.
- I'm sorry. I didn't know
Orrin Hatch was out of his cage.
- Come on. Morning, sweetheart.
- Morning.
What are you gonna do today?
- Working in the workshop.
- I was thinking.
Maybe you'd feel better
if you got a job.
We've been over this.
Nobody's looking for a puppeteer
in today's wintry economic climate.
I know, honey,
but I thought, you know...
maybe something else
until this puppet thing turns around.
Derek Mantini
doesn't need a day job.
Not everybody can be
Derek Mantini.
I gotta get to the shop. We have
a shipment of kitty litter coming in.
Will you do me a favor?
Will you take a look at Elijah today?
- He's not feeling very good again.
- Which one is Elijah again?
- The chimp, honey.
- Yeah, okay.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Man On TV]On the lighter side of
the news, in Westchester County today...
puppeteer Derek Mantini
thrill edonlookers as he performed
The Belle of Amherst...
with a 60-foot
Emily Dickinson puppet.
How dreary to be somebody.
How public, like a frog,
to tell one's name the live long day.
[ Scoffs ]
Gimmicky bastard.
[Poetry Recitation Continues]
You don't know lucky you are,
being a monkey.
- Because consciousness...
- [Elijah Chitters ]
is a terrible curse.
I think, I feel...
I suffer.
And I'll ask in return
is the opportunity to do my work.
And they won't allow it...
- [Elijah Chitters ]
- because I raise issues.
[ Classical ]
[Woman On Tape] While we enjoy
the pleasures of an uneasy love...
and abandon ourselves
to fornication...
we were spared God's severity.
[Man On Tape]Say no more, I beg you,
and cease from complaints like these...
which are so far removed
from the true depths of love.
- [Stereo: Woman Singing Opera]
- Look, a puppet show!
Okay, honey, just for a minute.
Mommy's waiting.
[Woman]Even during
the celebration of Mass...
when our prayers should be pure...
Lewd visions of these pleasures
take such a hold. ..
upon my unhappy soul...
that my thoughts are
on their very wantonness...
instead of my prayers.
[Opera Continues In Background]
Sometimes my thoughts
are betrayed. ..
by the movement of my body.
[Man]l took my fill
of my wretched pleasures in you...
and this was
the sum total of my love.
[Opera Continues]
You motherfucker!
[Birds Chirping]
[Shop Bell Rings]
Oh, Craig!
Honey, not again!
Why do you do this
to yourself, honey?
I'm a puppeteer.
[Elevator Bell Dings]
Seven and a half, right?
- Uh, yeah.
- I'll take you through it.
[Alarm Ringing]
- [Bell Dings, Alarm Continues]
- Seven and a half.
Thank you.
[Alarm Stops]
Welcome to Lestercorp.
How may we meet your filing needs?
No. Um... my name's
Craig Schwartz.
- I have an interview with Dr. Lester.
- Oh.
- Please have a seat, Mr.Juarez.
- Schwartz.
- Pardon?
I-I'm sorry. I have no idea
what you're saying to me right now.
- My name is Schwartz.
- My name is Warts?
[Intercom Beeps]
Mr.Juarez?
Oh. Yes?
- Chest?
- I said, "Yes?"
You suggest what?
I'm sorry...
I have no time for piddling suggestions
from mumbling job applicants.
Besides, Dr. Lester
will see you now.
Come in, Mr.Juarez.
[ Chuckles ]
- Actually, my name
is Craig Schwartz, Dr. Lester.
- Security!
No, sir, it's-- It's just
a little mix-up with your secretary.
My name is Craig Schwartz.
I tried to explain that to her.
She's not my secretary.
- She's what they call
an executive liaison.
- Ah.
And I am not banging her,
if that's what you're implying.
No, sir, not at all.
I think I must have simply misspoke.
Ah. Well, now,
tell me, Dr. Schwartz...
what do you feel
you can bring to Lestercorp?
Uh, well, sir,
I'm an excellent filer.
Are you? All right.
Let's see about that.
Tell me, which of these two letters
comes first? This one or this one?
The symbol on the left
is not a letter, sir.
Damn, you're good.
[ Chuckles ]
- I was trying to trick you.
- I see.
Well, then, put these in order.
Yes, sir.
Floris, get Guinness on the phone.
[Chuckles]
[Floris ] Yes, sir.
Genghis Khan Capone. Fine.
Damn fine woman-- Floris.
I don't know how she puts up with
this speech impediment of mine.
You don't have
a speech impediment, Dr. Lester.
Flattery will get you
everywhere, my boy.
I'm afraid have to trust
Floris on that one.
You see,
she's got her doctorate...
in speech impedimentology
from Case Western.
I apologize if you can't understand
a word I'm saying.
No, I understand perfectly.
Oh, it's very kind
of you to lie.
You see, I've been very lonely...
in my isolated tower
of indecipherable speech.
- [Slaps Knee]
- You got the job.
- Any questions?
- Well, just one.
Why are these ceilings so low?
Low overhead, my boy!
We pass the savings on to you.
But seriously,
that'll all be covered in orientation.
- [ Sighs ]
- [TV: Theme Music]
[ Man ] Welcome to
the seven and a half floor
of the Mertin Flemmer Building.
As you'll now be spending
your work day here, it is important...
that you learn a bit about the history
of this famous floor.
- Hello, Don.
- Hello, Wendy.
Don, I was wondering,
do you know why...
our workplace
has such low ceilings?
It's an interesting story.
Many years ago in the late 1 800s...
James Mertin, an I rish ship captain,
came to this town...
and decided to erect
an office building.
He called this building the
Mertin Flemmer Building after himself...
and someone else, who local legend
has it was named Flemmer.
Well, one day, old Captain Mertin
received an unexpected visitor.
- Captain Mertin?
- Aye. What want ye, girl child?
I'm not a child, but rather
an adult lady of miniature proportions.
I see. Well, if it's
charity you're after...
be gone with ye,
you foul demon!
I'm not asking for alms...
but, rather, the ear of a kind man
with a noble heart.
[Captain]
Well, speak then, if you must.
Captain Mertin, I'm afraid hat
the world was not built with me in mind.
Doorknobs are too high,
chairs are unwieldy...
and high-ceilinged rooms
mock my stature.
Why cannot there be a place for me
to work that's safe and comfortable?
[Captain]
Thy story has moved me like no other.
Therefore, I shall make ye--
[ Groans ] me wife.
And-- And I shall build
a floor for ye...
between the seventh and the eighth
in me own building...
so at least there'll be one place
on God's green earth...
where ye and your accursed kind
can live in peace.
So that's the story
of even and a half.
Since the rents are considerably lower,
this floor has been adopted...
by businesses which,
for one reason or another,
have been forced to cut corners.
After all, the overhead is low.
[ Both Laughing ]
[Theme Music]
[Music Stops]
Moving story, huh?
Unfortunately, the story's bullshit.
Listen, I'm Craig Schwartz.
I'm just starting out at Lestercorp.
Where are you starting out?
[ Sighs ]
[Orrin Hatch]
Shut up! Shut up!
- Shut up! Shut up!
- [Neighbor Banging On Wall]
Hey, shut up!
- [Craig]Shut up! I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry, honey.
Sorry, honey.
[ Squawks ]
- Sorry, honey.
- [Banging On Wall]
- [Neighbor]Shut up!
- Sorry!
- Help! She's locking me in a cage.
- Isn't that cute?
- I just taught him that today.
- Yeah, that's adorable.
- [Bottle Clattering]
- [ Elijah Shrieks ]
- You want to do some dishes for me?
- Put that down.
Here, Elijah.
Here you go.
You know, I have an appointment
tomorrow with Elijah's shrink.
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah. I think we're finally
getting down to the bottom...
of this acid stomach,
aren't we?
- Come here.
- [ Elijah Shrieks ]
-Just get down from the--
- She thinks that it's
some sort of childhood trauma.
- Feelings of inadequacy
as a chimp, you know?
- Mm-hmm.
Careful.
Isn't that interesting?
- Mm-hmm.
- I find it really interesting.
[Elijah Chittering, Shrieking]
So, honey, have you thought any more
about us having a baby?
Uh... you know,
I think it's just so tough right now...
- economically and all...
- Mm-hmm.
that I think maybe we should just wait
and see if this job thing pays off.
- You know?
- Okay.
I was thinking about
what you were saying...
- about the orientation film
being bullshit.
- Yes?
I think maybe
you're on to something.
- And 50 other lines
to get into a girl's pants.
- [ Laughs ] No, no!
No, I was just talking about the--
you know, about the film.
Here's the thing.
If you ever got me, you wouldn't have
a clue what to do with me.
[ Chuckles ]
I wasn't-- I was talking about the film.
[ Chuckles Nervously, Sighs ]
Ooh, what magic those fingers could
work on the right cabinet, mmm.
Maybe you could alphabetize me.
And don't forget...
" I " comes before... " U."
Floris, I think you're very nice...
but the truth is that...
I'm in love with someone else.
I'm afraid I have no idea
what you're saying to me.
- You bastard.
- What?
Don't toy with Floris, Schwartz.
- Oh, no--
- If I was 80 years younger,
I'd box your ears.
I wasn't toying with her, sir.
I wouldn't--
- Pardon me. How old are you, sir?
- 1 05.
Carrot juice, and lots of it.
I swear, sometimes it's not worth it.
I piss orange.
And I have to piss sitting down...
Like a goddamn girly-girl,
every 1 5 minutes.
- Mm.
- But nobody wants to die.
Ah, to be a young man again,
eh, Schwartz? [ Laughs ]
Maybe then Floris
would care for me.
But the elderly have so much to offer,
sir. They're our link with history.
I don't wanna be
your goddamn link, damn ya.
I want to feel Floris's
naked thighs next to mine.
I want my body to inspire lust...
in that beautiful, complex woman.
I want her to shiver
with a spasm of ecstasy...
Schwartz, as I penetrate her wet--
Dr. Lester, while I'm flattered
you would share your feelings with me...
perhaps the workplace is not
the most suitable environment
for this type of discussion.
All right. You're right.
I'll tell you what.
Meet me after work today
at Jerry's Juiceteria on Lex...
and I'll spill
my goddamn guts for ya.
No, I won't be late, Lotte.
I just have to, you know...
Listen to Lester's sexual fantasies
and drink carrot juice for a while.
It's a job thing, really.
Yeah. So, I'll talk to you later, okay?
Yeah. You too.
Gotta go back to work.
Okay, bye.
Hi. Do you know that I don't even know
your name or where you work?
Yeah.
Um... okay, how about this?
If I can guess your name
in three tries, you have to come
have a drink with me tonight.
- [ Sighs ] Why not?
- [Elevator Bell Dings]
- [Elevator Alarm Ringing]
- Okay.
You look like a...
Bar--
Ru--
Bell-- Lu--
L-- Carol--
Ta-- Shar--
Susann--
Emm...ily--
Mar...lar--
Maax...ine--
M-M-M-- Maxine?
Yeah!
Who told you?
Nobody told me. That just came out.
Isn't that odd?
So where do you live
and stuff?
[ Sighs ]
I am dubious...
but I don't welsh.
Okay, meet me
at The Stuck Pig, 7:00.
If you're late, I walk.
Nubile. Blonde.
Wet with desire.
Me in leather.
A harness, if you like.
And all eyes, Craig,
are upon me as I speak.
" Ladies," I begin.
" I am the love god Eros."
They like that.
" I intoxicate you.
My spunk is, to you,
manna from heaven."
Dr. Lester, this is
all really fascinating and stuff...
but I gotta...
get back home to my wife.
- You have a wife. I'd like to meet her.
- Yes, sir.
Shall we say dinner Thursday?
You can come, too, if you like.
[Laughs]
Get that? That was a joke.
You hear what I said? You can come too.
- That was a good one.
- [ Laughs ]
- All right. Thank you.
- Yeah.
[Car Horn Honks]
[Men Speaking Japanese]
Maxine. Maxine.
- I made it, Maxine.
-Just.
Buy you a drink, Maxine?
Are you married?
- Yeah. But enough about me.
- Yeah.
- What'll you have?
- I'll have more
of the same, please, Barry.
And I'll have, uh,
a light beer or something.
[Barry] Hay.
So, uh...
I don't know--
I, uh-- I like you.
- I don't know what it is
about you. I just--
- My tits?
- No! No, no, no, no.
- No?
- It's your energy,
the way you carry yourself.
- You're not a fag, are you?
No. I am really
attracted to you.
" I am really attracted to you."
Christ, you are a fag.
- Well, we can share recipes
if you like, Darlene.
- No, wait!
- I love your tits. I wanna fuck 'em.
- Now we're gettin' somewhere.
- Not a chance.
- [ Men Laughing ]
So tell me about yourself, huh?
If you can get your mind
out of the gutter long enough, dog boy.
Well, I'm a puppeteer.
- I-- I've been--
- Check.
[Lock Rattling]
Hey.
- Hey.
- I'm sorry I'm so late.
I just-- Lester just wouldn't...
Let me get away.
Hi, Elijah. We're supposed to have
dinner with him on Thursday...
but I can get us out of it,
if you want.
He's like this insane old leech,
and it's kind of amusing...
- once you get past
how disgusting it actually is.
- Did you eat?
No. I'm not hungry. I'm sorry I didn't
call. It was just hard to get away.
- I was worried.
- I'm sorry.
- You know... [ Chuckles ]
- [Elijah Shrieking]
you wanted me to work.
[Bottle Cap Clatters Onto Floor]
- How was your evening?
- Well...
Tom-Tom's puncture wound
is infected.
- The ferret?
- The iguana.
Right.
So I just dressed the wound...
and I've just been feeding everyone
and putting everybody to bed.
- You want a beer?
- No. I think I'm going to go to bed.
Elijah's gonna sleep
with us tonight.
- I don't think he's feeling very well.
- Okay.
Hm.
Well, you know what? I'm gonna go
in my workshop for a little while.
- But I'll be in a little while.
- Okay.
[Craig] Tell me, Craig,
why do you love puppeteering?
[Sighs]
Well, Maxine,
I'm not sure exactly.
Perhaps it's the idea of becoming
someone else for a little while.
Being inside another skin...
thinking differently,
moving differently...
feeling differently.
Interesting, Craig.
Would you like
to be inside my skin...
think what I think,
feel what I feel?
More than anything, Maxine.
It's good in here, Craig.
It's better than
your wildest dreams.
You're not somebody
I could get interested in, Craig.
You play with dolls.
Puppets, Maxine. It's the idea
of being inside someone else's skin...
- and seeing what they see
and feeling what they feel.
- Yikes!
- It's just that, well--
Please let me explain.
- [Elevator Bell Dings]
- [Alarm Ringing]
- I've never done this before, but...
I feel something for you,
and I've never felt this way before...
you know, about anybody,
n-not even my wife.
And I just-- I really feel
that you and I belong together, Maxine.
- Oh!
- [Ringing Fades]
[ Sighs ]
Shit.
Hm.
- [Phone Ringing]
- [Man]See you later.
Hello. Mailroom.
Yeah. Yeah.
What's the file number?
- 3-2-3-6-4. Yep.
- [Phone Ringing]
[ Squishing Sound ]
[ Gasps ]
- [Wind Howling]
- Oh! [ Shouting ]
[Loud Crunching, Chewing]
[Slurps, Gulps]
[Footsteps]
Oh, you know what?
The puppeteer told me he loved me today.
I know, I can't think
of anything more pathetic.
[ Chuckling ]
I'm sorry.
Good afternoon, sir.
- The Broad Hurst Theater, please.
- [Door Closes]
Hey, say, uh...
ain't you that actor guy?
Yes.
John, uh-- What is, uh--
John, um, uh--
Uh, don't tell me.
Maplethorpe?
- Malkovich.
- Malkovich. Right, right. Okay.
- Yeah. I thought you were
all right in that one movie.
- Thankyou.
The one where you played
a jewel thief.
- I never played a jewel thief.
- No?
- Who am I thinkin' of?
- I don't know.
Just, uh--
No, no, I'm pretty sure it was you.
- The, uh-- 'Cause, uh--
- [Whooshing Sound]
- [Popping Sound]
- [ Grunts ]
[ Panting ]
Yeah. Absolutely, doll. Yeah.
I'm just about to close up.
Wanna meet at the Pig in 20 minutes?
Cool. Bye.
I'm splittin' for the day, puppet man.
Lock up for me, okay?
- Don't you wanna know
what happened to me?
- No.
- Please, this is important.
- Better be.
It is.
There's a tiny door
in my office, Maxine.
It's a portal,
and it takes you inside John Malkovich.
You see the world
through John Malkovich's eyes...
and then after about 15 minutes,
you're spit out...
into a ditch on the side
of the New Jersey Turnpike.
Sounds great!
Who the fuck is John Malkovich?
Oh, he's an actor. He's one of the great
American actors of the 20th century.
Oh, yeah?
What's he been in?
Lots of things.
That jewel thief movie, for example.
He's very well respected.
Anyway, the point is...
this is a very odd thing.
It's supernatural,
for lack of a better word.
I mean, it raises
all sorts of philosophical-type
questions, you know...
about the nature of self,
about the existence of a soul.
You know, am I me?
Is Malkovich Malkovich?
I had a piece of wood in my hand.
I don't have it anymore.
Where is it?
Did it disappear?
How could that be?
Is it still in Malkovich's head?
I don't know!
Do you see what a metaphysical
can of worms this portal is?
I don't see how I could go on living
my life the way I've lived it before.
[Phone Ringing]
- Yeah?
- So I've been thinking,
is this Malkovich fellow appealing?
Maxine! Yes, of course, Maxine.
He's a celebrity.
Good. We'll sell tickets.
- Tickets to Malkovich?
- Exactly.
Two hundred dollars a pop.
But, Maxine, there's something,
I don't know, like profound here.
I don't know if maybe
we should exploit it. You think?
I need you for this, Craigy.
You're my man on the inside.
You need me?
I'm your man?
- Sure, whatever.
- [Door Opens, Dog Barks]
- Hey, everybody, I'm home.
- [Elijah Chittering]
- Treats for everyone.
- [ Whispers ] Maxine?
- [ Maxine ] Yeah?
- We don't know
the significance of this thing.
- It might be dangerous to toy with?
- [ Lotte Chattering ]
Well, I'll protect you, doll face.
- Bye-bye.
- [Dog Barking]
[Line Clicks]
- Who was that?
- [Elijah Shrieking]
I'm going to be working a lot
of late nights with this partner...
because Lestercorp's open
during the day, so I'll be
working a lot of late nights.
But it's a good thing, 'cause it's gonna
get us out of the hole financially...
'cause we're gonna
turn it into a business.
But I don't understand.
There's not--
There's no such thing as a hole,
or a portal, into somebody's brain.
Yes, there is.
A brain, or soul or whatever.
I was inside John Malkovich lookin' out.
- Really?
- Yep.
- I wanna try it.
- Pardon me?
I want to be
John Malkovich, tomorrow.
That'd be perfect,
'cause then I can meet your partner.
The thing is, Lestercorp's open during
the day, so we can't go during the day.
But if you want to,
we can do it right now.
- Now? Right now?
- Tonight. Right now,
on the way to Lester's.
I'll meet you on the side of the road
by the New Jersey Turnpike.
I'm scared.
You don't have to do this, you know.
No.
No, l-l wanna go.
- You sure? Okay.
- Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
[Wind Howling]
[ Humming ]
[Lotte]It's wet.
Weird.
That's nice. Oh!
[Giggles]
Oh!
[Laughing]
Oh, mmm!
Oh! Mmm.
God. [Chuckles]
I feel sexy.
[Popping Sound]
Lotte, are you all right?
Craig! Craig,
I gotta go back!
- No!
- Maybe tomorrow.
- No! I gotta go back now!
- We'll talk about it later.
Wow!
Being inside did something to me.
I knew who I was.
It's like everything made sense.
I-l knew who I was.
But you weren't you.
You were John Malkovich.
God, I was.
I was, wasn't I ?
I was--
I was John Malkovich.
I was John fucking Malkovich!
- Take me back, Craig.
- We're late for Lester.
So tell me, Lotte,
can you understand a word I'm saying?
Oh, yes, Dr. Lester.
Absolutely.
You were just explaining
the nutritional value...
of ingesting minerals
through a colloidal form which
I couldn't agree more with.
Oh! Be still, my heart.
Dr. Lester, would you mind pointing
me in the direction of the restroom?
With the greatest pleasure, my dear.
You go up the grand escalier...
and once atop the stairs
you'll want to enter the, uh...
fifth door on my left.
- Watch the step down. It's sunken.
- Okay. Thankyou.
"Malkovich Physical Development. "
What do you think Lester's relationship
with John Malkovich is?
That portal's been boarded up forever.
I bet Lester's not even aware of it--
him-- the portal. Why?
No reason.
I was just thinking.
Do you think that it's kind of weird
that John Malkovich has a portal?
Do you think that it might have
some sort of significance, for example?
I don't know.
Why do you think that?
I don't even care.
I think it's kind of sexy
that John Malkovich has a portal.
Sort of like
it's like he's a vagina.
It's sort of vaginal,
like he has a--
he has a penis and a vagina.
It's sort of like...
Malkovich's feminine side.
I like that.
"Visit J.M. Inc.
Mertin Flemmer Building.
Nightly from 9:00 p.m. to 4:00 a.m."
Sounds good.
Oblique but intriguing. Phone it in.
- Want me to phone it in?
- No.
[Door Opens]
- Lotte!
- Hi.
- I heard your voice.
- What are you doing here?
Is this your partner?
She's pretty.
I had to do the Malkovich ride again,
you know? Is this her?
- Hi. You're Craig 's wife?
- Yeah. Hi.
Lotte, Maxine.
Maxine, Lotte.
- Have you done Malkovich yet?
- Uh, hi. Yeah, I want to place an ad.
Okay.
"Ever want to be someone else?"
No, that's the ad,
but we can talk about you in a minute.
"Ever want to be someone else?
Now you can. Visit J.M. Inc. "
Inc. Mertin.
M-E-R-T-l-N.
Flemmer.
You should really be at work.
[ Sighs ]
I've been going over and over
my experience last night, Craig.
It was amazing.
I've decided--
that I'm a transsexual.
- I know it's the craziest thing, Craig!
- What, are you fuckin' nuts?
No. It's just that for the first time,
everything just felt right.
I've got to make sure.
But if the feeling is still there...
I'm going to talk to Dr. Feldman
about sexual reassignment surgery.
This is absurd!
Besides, Feldman is an allergist.
If you're going to do something,
do it right.
You get these half-assed ideas,
and then you do a half-assed job.
Just drop it.
It's just that I really, you know,
like Dr. Feldman. All right?
So I thought that
I would ask him his opinion.
Is there something
so terrible about that?
-Why do you always yell at me like this?
-Sweetie, I'm sorry.
It's just a phase. It's the thrill
of seeing through somebody else's eyes.
Okay? It'll pass.
Don't stand in the way
of my actualization as a man.
- [Phone Clicks Onto Cradle]
- Lethergo, Craig.
- Okay.
- I mean him.
Right now?
Uh-huh.
It's the middle of the day.
How am I going to get her past Lester?
- Yawn. Figure it out.
- Okay.
Let's go.
Come on.
- Bye.
[ Chuckles ]
[Door Closes]
[Touch Tone Dialing]
Davey, it's Max.
Listen, can you get me
John Malkovich's home phone?
" But what I had been through.
I am hungry as the winter.
I am sick, anxious, poor as a beggar.
Fate has tossed me hither and thither.
I have been everywhere.
Everywhere.
- [Lotte]So strong.
- But wherever I have been...
- every minute, day and night...
- I want that voice.
- my soul has been full
of mysterious anticipations.
- My soul has been full...
- of mysterious anticipation.
- I feel the approach of happiness.
Anya, I see it coming."
[Phone Ringing]
[ Clicks ]
- Yeah?
- [ Maxine ] Mr. John Malkovich?
- Yeah. Who's calling?
- [ Gasps ] Oh, my goodness!
You don't know me,
but I know you.
I'm a great admirer of yours.
How did you get this number?
Well... it's just that l--
I-- I dream about you.
And well, even speaking to you now
has gotten me sort of excited, you know?
[Lotte Chuckles] Wow, the way
this woman's talking to him.
Listen, I really don't
find this amusing.
- Don't call here anymore, okay?
- Well!
My nipples are at attention,
General Malkovich, sir.
[Lotte Giggles]
What, her nipples?
[Maxine]So, listen,
why don't we have dinner tonight?
Bernardo's? 8:00?
I really want to see you. I just loved
you in that jewel thief movie.
[ Line Clicks ]
[ Beeps ]
[Lotte] You're not gonna
meet her there? Come on!
- [ Rewinding ]
- Meet her. Meet her. Meet her there.
- Meet her there!
- [ Malkovich's Voice ]
"...as the winter.
I am sick, anxious, poor as a beggar.
- Meet her there!
- Fate has tossed me hit her and hit her.
I have been everywhere.
Everywhere.
But wherever I have been,
every minute, day and night...
- Meet her there. Meet her there.
- My soul has been full...
- Yes!
- of mysterious anticipations. "
- How was it?
- I have to go back at
8:00 exactly, tonight.
- Why?
- Don't crowd me, Craig.
- Excuse me. Are you John Malkovich?
- Yes, I am.
Wow. You really are great in that movie
where you play that retard.
Oh, Thankyou very much.
- I have a cousin who's a retard.
- Oh. Thankyou.
So, as you might imagine,
it means a lot to me...
to see retards...
portrayed on the silver screen
so compassionately.
Well, thank you very much.
I appreciate it.
Good night.
- [Lotte]Maxine? It's Maxine.
- Hi.
I'm so glad you decided to come.
I'm Maxine.
I'm John.
How do you do?
Good. [ Chuckles ]
I wasn't sure
I was going to come...
but I felt, uh, oddly compelled.
[Lotte]
You're so beautiful.
The way you're looking at me--
I mean, at him-- at us.
[ Laughs ]
[Lotte]I've never been
looked at like this by a woman before.
[Exhales]
I think I'm sweating.
I must say,
I was intrigued by your voice.
And the funny thing is, Mr. Malkovich...
my voice is probably
the least intriguing thing about me.
[Lotte Laughing]
[ Laughing ]
So, I mean-- So, how was it?
What was he doing?
He wasn't doing anything really.
He was just hanging
around his apartment.
I think he's probably just a really...
uh, lonely guy.
See, men can feel
unfulfilled, too, Lotte.
I'm glad you're coming
to realize that.
You shouldn't be so quick to assume
that switching bodies...
is gonna be the answer
to your problems.
You're right, Craig.
You're right.
You know what I was thinking?
I was thinking that maybe...
we should invite Maxine
over for dinner one night...
because you guys are partners
and I thought that might be
a really nice gesture.
- I think she'd like that. What?
- Maxine?
The thing is, there's been
some tension between us at work--
business stuff--
and I would hate to expose you to that.
[ Scoffs ]
It'll be okay.
I'll cook my lasagna,
we'll smoke a joint, and...
tensions will just melt away.
Now, when you say that I can be
somebody else, what do you mean exactly?
Well, we mean exactly that.
We can put you inside
someone else's body for 1 5 minutes.
Can I be anybody that I wanna be?
Well... you--
- Actually--
- You can be John Malkovich.
That's perfect! It's my second choice,
but it's wonderful.
It's--
[ Sobbing ]
I'm a fat man.
I am sad and fat--
Two hundred dollars?
Oh. Oh, uh, yes.
- [Door Opens, Wind Humming]
- Okay.
You gotta crawl in there.
Oh, my God.
[ Panting ]
Oh.
[Wind Howling]
No, that's what I'm saying. See, I don't
really need an extra bath mat.
So if I get the set,
would it be possible...
if I could just get maybe three...
extra hand towels--
uh, if I get the set--
instead of the bathmat?
- [Woman On Phone]
Yes, sir. Sure, we can do that.
- Great.
That sounds good.
And for the color, periwinkle?
[Woman]Oh, I'm sorry.
We 're out of stock in periwinkle.
Do you want to back order?
No. I'll, uh... go with the loden.
Would you like to order anything else?
What is the difference between
the foot-pampering looped cotton rug...
and the bath mat?
[Popping Sound]
[Laughing]
You're my friends.
Thankyou.
Did you know that
Eskimos have not one...
but...
49 words for snow?
- Mm.
- It's because they have so much of it.
[Laughing]
So much snow.
After dinner,
I'll show you my puppets.
Ah.
After dinner, I'll introduce you
to my chimp Elijah.
He has an ulcer right now
due to suppressed childhood trauma...
- but we're working through it.
- [ Chittering ]
[ Whispers ]
Psychotherapy.
Oh.
- This the bedroom?
- Yeah.
[ All Laughing ]
The thing is,
the way that I see it...
is, I think the world is divided...
into those who go after what they want
and then those who don't, right?
- Right.
- The passionate ones--
the ones who go after
what they want--
well, they may not get
what they want.
[Laughing]
But-- But...
at least they remain vital.
- Yeah.
- [Craig] Yeah.
So when they lie on their death beds,
they have, um... few regrets.
Right?
[ Spits, Laughs ]
And the ones who don't go
after what they want...
well... who gives a shit
about them, anyway?
- God! Craig!
- Lotte!
I don't find you attractive, hm?
And, Lotte...
I'm smitten with you.
[Chuckles]lam,
but only when you're in Malkovich.
When I looked into his eyes last night,
I could feel you peering out.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Behind the stubble and the too prominent
brow and the male-pattern baldness...
I sensed your feminine longing.
- And it just slew me. [ Laughs ]
- [ Laughs ]
Oh, my God!
Oh!
Only as John, sweetie.
Sorry.
Hey, thanks for
a wonderful dinner.
No hard feelings, partner?
[Stereo: Rock]
[Wind Howling]
- [Phone Rings]
- J.M. Inc.
Hi. It's Lotte.
I'd like very much
to see you again.
Can you call him
and invite yourself over?
Um... when?
Mm... tonight...
after you close?
Okay, uh... 4:1 1 .
4:1 1 ?
- Thankyou, Maxine.
- You're welcome.
[Door Buzzer Buzzes]
Thanks so much
for having me over, sugarplum.
- I'm glad you called.
- [ Chuckles ]
Shall we to the boudoir?
A couple of minutes.
I'm early.
So do-- do you enjoy being...
an actor?
Sure. Yeah. It's--
It's very rewarding.
[ Sighs ]
Hi.
Oh.
[Malkovich Sighing]
[Lotte Giggling]
Oh, my sweet Maxine.
- My darling.
- I love you, Lotte.
[ Sighs, Moans ]
Did you call me Lotte?
Do you mind?
[ Chuckles ]
- No, not really.
- Mm.
- Oh!
- [Lotte]Oh, God.
- My sweet... beautiful Lotte.
- Oh!
Oh, Maxine!
[ Malkovich ]
Yes, Maxine. Yes.
[Lotte Whispers ]
Maxine, this is-- this is so right.
- [ Malkovich Moaning ]
- Oh! Oh, God.
[ Maxine, Malkovich Moaning ]
- [Unzipping]
- [Lotte, Malkovich Moaning]
[Lotte, Malkovich] Yes!
- Wow!
- [ Malkovich Moaning ]
- [Malkovich Grunts]
- Yes!
[ Grunts, Sighs ]
- You were him, weren't you?
- Yeah.
And he was with her!
We love her, Craig.
- "We "?
-John and me.
- Don't forget about me!
- Well, you have
the Maxine action figure to play with!
[Elijah Chittering]
I'm sorry.
That was nasty.
[Door Slams]
You are late, my little cowboy.
Are you torturing me on purpose?
- I've fallen in love.
- I don't think so.
You know why?
Because I've fallen in love!
And this is what people
who have fallen in love look like.
Well, you picked the unrequited variety.
It's very bad for the skin.
You're evil, Maxine.
Do you have any idea what it's like
to have two people look at you...
with total lust and devotion...
through the same pair of eyes?
Wow.
No, I don't suppose you would.
It's quite a thrill, Craigy.
[ Clicks Tongue ]
[ Door Slams ]
[ Horn Honking ]
[Dog Barks, Elijah Whimpers ]
[Barking Continues]
[Dog Whining]
- Aaah! What are you doing?
- [Elijah Screeches]
Oh, my God! Is that real?
What is that?
Yes! I don't know how to use it very
well, so don't make any sudden moves!
- [Barking]
- [ Whimpering ]
I'm serious!
I'm serious.
Suck my dick!
[Elijah Screams]
Shut up, okay?
Just shut up.
[ Screams ]
[ Dial Tone ]
[ Whimpering, Screaming ]
[ Sobbing ]
- Craig!
- Tell her you need to see her.
- [ Ringing ]
- [ Maxine ] J.M. Inc.
Be all that someone else can be.
I need to see you.
Sweetie!
Oh, I had so much fun
with you last night.
Shoot.
But it's business hours.
[ Whispering ] Tell her what the hell,
close early, live dangerously.
Say it.
What the hell, you know?
[ Nervous Laugh ]
Live dangerously.
Close early.
Ooh, doll.
I love this new
devil-may-care side of you.
All righty. I'll track down loverboy
and see both of you in one hour.
Exactamundo.
[Hangs Up ]
[ Coughs ]
Craig!
[ Screams ]
What's the matter with you?
Stop it!
Sit up, okay?
Just sit up. Just sit up.
- [ Crying ]
-[Dog Barking, Elijah Shrieking]
[ Screaming ]
Help!
He's locking me in a cage!
- [Neighbor Banging On Wall]
- Shut up!
Shut up!
[ Elijah Whimpering ]
Was ever woman in this humor wooed?
Was ever woman in this humor won?
Tommy, can I take 1 5?
[ All Chattering ]
[Man]Goodnight, everybody.
See you back here at 9:00p.m. tomorrow.
- Oh!
- [ Grunting ]
Oh, Lotte.
Lotte, this is so good!
[ Grunting ]
[Craig]
My God! This is amazing.
- Lotte!
- I want to touch her breast.
Touch her breast.
Move right hand
across left breast now.
-Lotte!
-Move right hand across left breast now!
Move right hand
across left breast now.
- Holy shit, yes!
- [ Slurred Speech ] Holy shit, yes!
- Holy shit, he said what I said!
- Shit, he said what I said!
- Lotte? Is that you?
- Yes, yes, sweetheart.
Yes, sweetheart, yes.
What the fuck is going on?
That's not me! I didn't say that.
- Oh, Lotte.
- Oh, Maxine. Oh--
Something was making me talk.
Some goddamn thing
was making me move.
- I've gotta get out of here.
- Oh, doll face!
It was just, uh,
your passion for me taking hold.
No, doll face. I know what
my passion taking hold feels like.
Bye!
I did it!
I made him move his arms
across your girlfriend's glorious tit!
Oh, and. ..
I made him talk sort of.
It's just a matter of practice
before Malkovich...
is nothing more than another puppet
hanging next to my work table.
[ Muffled Whining ]
I'll tell you about it
when I get home, okay? All right?
[ Muffled ]
Craig! Craig! I wanna--
- [ Crying ]
- [Door Slams]
[Locks Latching]
No, man, I'm sorry to--
I'm sorry to have called you like that,
but I was just really, really scared.
I was so freaked out.
I mean, it was like... somebody was
just moving all the way through me...
moving my arms, moving my hands,
talking for me.
I mean, literally,
I feel like I'm going crazy, Charlie.
- I'm sure you're not going crazy.
- You don't understand, man.
- It was like nothing
I've ever felt before.
- Yeah, yada, yada, yada.
- Were you stoned?
- Yes. Yes, I was--
Jesus.
Yes! Yes, I was stoned.
But what-- That doesn't have
anything to do with it.
Charlie, someone was talking
through my mouth.
You were stoned.
Case closed. End of story.
- How hot is this babe?
- You know what?
Maybe it was this
Lotte woman talking...
because it could have been her
talking through me.
Because this--
the weird thing is...
this Maxine likes
to call me Lotte.
Ouch. That is hot.
Maybe she's using you
to channel some dead, lesbian lover.
Sounds like my kind of gal. Let me know
when you're done with her, yeah?
What are you talking about? Done with
her, man? Tonight really freaked me out.
You're nuts to let a girl go
that calls you Lotte.
I'll tell you that as a friend.
Charlie, I don't know
anything about the girl.
- She could be, like,
a fucking witch or something.
- That's even better!
Hot, lesbian witches.
Think about it. It's fucking genius.
I gotta know the truth, Charlie.
The truth is for suckers, Johnny boy.
[ Whistles ]
[Horn Honks]
[Bell Dings, Alarm Ringing]
Thanks.
This way.
[Bell Dinging]
[Alarm Stops]
Excuse me, sir.
Exactly what, uh, type of service...
does this company provide?
You get to be John Malkovich
for 1 5 minutes.
Two hundred clams.
I see.
- No cutting, by the way. No cutting!
- Hey, what the hell?
[ Angry Shouting ]
Ah! Ow!
Come on! Break it up!
Break it up! Cut it out!
- Everybody gets--
-[Man]It's him. It's John Malkovich.
I'm sorry, Mr. Malkovich.
I hope we didn't hurt you too terribly.
Get inside!
- Darling!
- What the fuck is going on?
- [Craig]Uh, uh, John Malkovich.
- Huh?
Mr. Malkovich, sir.
Uh, um--
- Mr. Malkovich, I think I can explain.
- Yeah, explain.
My name is Craig Schwartz...
and we operate
a little business here...
that simulates, for our clientele,
well, the--
the experience of--
of-- of being you, actually.
- Simulates?
- Yeah, after a fashion.
- What exactly does that mean?
- Well, it's hard to describe.
- I want to do it then.
- That would pale in comparison
to the actual experience.
- I want to do it!
- Right now Mr. Hiroshi's in the tube--
- Let him do it, Craig.
- Of course.
Right this way, Mr. Malkovich,
compliments of the house.
[ Whispers ]
Jesus.
What happens when a man
goes through his own portal?
We'll see.
[ Panting ]
[ Gasps, Whimpers ]
[ Gasps, Screams ]
[People Chattering]
[Piano]
Malkovich.
Malkovich, Malkovich.
Malkovich, Malkovich, Malkovich?
- Malkovich, Malkovich.
- Malkovich?
- Malkovich!
- Malkovich.
Malkovich.
[ Laughs ]
- Malkovich!
- Malkovich, Malkovich
- Malkovich.
- Malkovich!
Malkovich, Malkovich
- Malkovich, Malkovich
- Malkovich!
[ Grunting ]
[ Yelling ]
- How was it?
- It was amazing this time.
- That was no simulation!
- I know. I'm sorry.
It's such an honor.
I have been to the dark side. I have
seen a world that no man should see!
Really? For most people,
it's a rather pleasant experience.
That portal is mine,
and it must be sealed forever...
for the love of God.
But, Mr. Malkovich, sir,
with all due respect...
I discovered that portal.
- It's my livelihood. Do you understand?
- It's my head, Schwartz!
It's my head!
I will see you in court!
What makes you think I won't be seeing
what you're seeing...
in court?
Hey, Malkovich, think fast!
[ High-pitched Squeal ]
Fuck!
Dinner.
[Lotte] You know, Craig,
once this was a relationship...
built on love.
Well, you gave up that claim...
after the first time
you stuck your dick in Maxine, Lotte.
You fell in love
with her first, Craig.
Yeah, but I didn't do anything about it,
out of respect for our marriage.
You didn't do anything
about it, Craig...
out of respect for the fact
that she wouldn't let you
near her with a ten-foot pole!
That's true.
God, Lotte, what have I become?
My wife in a cage with a monkey.
Craig.
I need to go to the bathroom
and take a shower.
What am l, some kind of monster?
I don't want to be a monster, Lotte.
I don't want to.
Craig, you're not a monster. No.
I know you're not a monster, honey.
You're just--
You're just...
a very, very confused man.
I love you so much.
I love you.
- [Phone Dial Tone, Dialing]
- Come on, Craig.
[ Ringing ]
-J.M. Inc.
- [ Lotte ] Maxine?
Lotte.
I've been thinking about us, you know?
And, uh--
- We have to meet.
- Um, okay.
I'll see you in Malkovich
in one hour.
[ Muffled ] Craig!
[ Moans ]
I hate you.
[ Whimpering ]
[Crying]
[Chimp Screeching]
[Man Shouting]
[Screeching Continues, Men Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
[ Screeching ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Excited Squeal ]
Oh, Elijah!
You really are magnificent.
[Phone Ringing]
-J.M. Inc.
- [ Lotte ] Maxine!
Honey pie! I was just heading out
the door to meet you.
No, listen, Maxine. It hasn't been me
in Malkovich the last time.
It's been that
son of a bitch Craig.
He's had me locked in the cage
with my chimp, holding a gun to my head.
- Oh, my God!
- He made me call you.
I'm sorry, Maxine.
It's been him the whole time.
I'm so sorry.
That's horrible.
I miss you so much, Maxine.
So-- But--
- Okay, that was Craig
inside of Malkovich?
- Yes, it was him.
It's because he's
a puppeteer, I think.
Well, boy, I'm-- Uh--
I'm surprised.
That's pretty impressive.
- What?
- So if Craig can control Malkovich...
- and I can control Craig--
- But, Maxine...
I thought it was me
that you loved!
I do.
[ Lotte Panting ]
It's confusing, you know?
This is a very confusing situation.
I know.
- Listen, I should really
get going, okay?
- [Thunder Rumbling]
- 'Cause I'm gonna be
late for Malkovich now.
- No.
- What?
- We'll talk about this later, Lotte.
- Maxine! Wait! Maxine!
- Okay?
[ Hangs Up ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Siren Wails In Distance]
- [Siren Grows Louder]
- [Door Buzzer Buzzing]
- [ Buzzing Continues ]
- What the fuck do you want?
I can explain
about the portal, darling.
Listen, don't con me, Maxine.
I don't know
who the hell you people are...
but this insanity is now over.
Oh, shut up.
Craigy. Craig.
Schwartzy, are you in there?
[ Loud Grunting ]
[ Strained Voice ]
How did you know it was me?
Lotte called me.
She escaped your evil clutches.
Really? Well, I'm really sorry
I did that, Maxine...
but I'm really in love with you, and
I didn't know how else to be with you.
Hmm.
Apparently you can control
this Malkovich fellow now?
Yes, I'm getting better all the time.
I'll say you are.
Hey, let's do it
on his dining room table.
- Then we'll make him
eat an omelet off of it.
- No!
- Shut up, you overrated sack of shit!
- [ Laughs ]
Craigy.
[ Rings ]
Yes?
Hi, Dr. Lester.
It's Lotte Schwartz,
Craig's wife.
Oh! Yes.
Oh, my God.
You'll catch your death out here.
Look at you. You're soaking wet.
Please come in, come in.
[Thunder Continues]
[ Chuckles ]
Here you are, my dear.
Thankyou.
[ Laughs ]
How's that?
Much better, thank you.
So, my dear...
what is it that brings you to my doorway
on such an inhospitable evening?
Well, Dr. Lester...
see, l, uh--
I have a very unhealthy obsession
with John Malkovich.
I see.
You mean, the performer.
Yes.
And what prompted you
to come to me with this issue?
Well, when I was here
with my husband for dinner...
I came upon a room that seemed to be
some sort of John Malkovich museum.
So I thought perhaps
maybe you would. ..
have some appreciation
for my state of mind.
You look so lovely, my dear...
standing here before the fire...
in my oversized man's robe.
Thankyou, Dr. Lester.
Tell me...
what is this strange power
that Malkovich exudes?
You've gotta help me understand because
all I think about is wanting to be him.
- Wanting to what?
- Wanting to be him.
Wanting to be John Malkovich.
Oh, I see.
Well, perhaps you can.
But, Dr. Lester--
I am not Dr. Lester.
I am Captain Mertin.
I don't understand.
It was 90 years ago
that I discovered a strange portal.
And--And I found that
this portalled to a vessel body...
and that I could live forever
by leaping from vessel to vessel.
- So Dr. Lester is such a vessel?
- Yes, he is.
You still there, sweets?
Hmm.
I figured out how to hang on
as long as I want.
It's all a matter of making friends
with the Malkovich body.
Rather than thinking of it
as an enemy that has to be
pounded into submission...
I've begun imagining it
as a really expensive suit...
that I enjoy wearing.
[Kissing Continues]
Ah, this illustrates...
how I will move into
my next vessel, Malkovich...
on his 44th birthday.
That's when he becomes ripe.
But I must enter
by midnight on that day.
After that, I'd get diverted into
the next newly forming infant vessel.
I don't want that to happen.
- I'd be absorbed.
- Absorbed? What does that mean?
Well, uh, trapped, held prisoner,
if you like, in the host's brain...
unable to control anything...
for ever doomed to watch the world
through someone else's eyes.
Now I'd like you
to meet some friends.
See, I got lonely
in Lester by myself...
so I figured out a way this time
to take others along with me.
Come.
[People Chattering]
Everyone, this is Lotte.
- Hi, Lotte!
- She's a new friend of mine.
Do a puppet show for me, Craig, honey.
You mean, with Malkovich?
- I'd love to see your work.
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah?
Okay.
This is something
that I call...
"Craig's Dance of Despair
and Disillusionment."
[Stereo: Orchestra]
[Continues]
[Ends ]
That was incredible!
You're-- You're brilliant!
You see, Maxine,
it isn't just playing with dolls.
Oh, my darling,
it's so much more!
It's playing with people.
[ Chuckles, Moans ]
Stay in him forever.
[ Gurgling, Grunting ]
My darling, how will we make
a living if our clientele
doesn't have access to our product?
Well, we'll have all the money
in Malkovich's bank account...
plus he does get
acting work occasionally.
[ Grunting ]
No, please!
- Shut up! We're trying to think here.
- Gee!
It is--
It is sort of like puppeteering.
- I-l-l like that about it.
- Exactly!
And no one would ever even
have to know it's not him.
And I could use
Malkovich's existing notoriety...
to launch my own puppeteering career.
Oh, Craigy.
Craigy, that's brilliant.
Oh. Oh.
So lovely. I've always wondered
what it would be like to have a penis.
- Now I'll know.
- [Lotte]Really? I know it's very--
Lotte?
We like you.
We can see you're a kind
and decent woman...
and so...
we've decided to offer you
a place in John Malkovich with us...
if you like.
Dr. Lester...
you've been so kind to me...
and trusting.
And...
there's just something I think you
should know about the Malkovich vessel.
[ Woman On Speaker ] John's here
to see you. Should I send him in?
Of course send him right in. Don't ever
keep him waiting again, you understand?
- [ Angry Muttering ]
- [Door Opens]
[ Clears Throat ]
Hey, John.
Great to see you.
Sorry about the cunt at reception.
Please, have a seat.
Can I get you anything?
Coffee? Water?
No, thank you.
- Teresa, get me chicken soup.
- Okay.
Chicken soup?
Larry? Uh...
I want to get right to the point.
From now on, I'm no longer an actor.
I'm a puppeteer.
Okay. Great.
And I would like
to redirect my career...
so that from now on
the name John Malkovich...
will be synonymous with puppets.
Sure. Sure.
No problemo.
Poof, you're a puppeteer.
Just let me make a couple calls.
[Laughing Continues]
Honey? Maxine?
Maxine?
I'm busy.
Maxine, honey, it's on!
[ Dramatic ]
Yeah, there's the truth,
and there are lies...
and, uh, art always tells the truth,
even when it's lying.
[Male Narrator]
The enigmatic John Malkovich...
one of the world's greatest entertainers
and the man who reinvented. ..
how we view puppeteering.
Tonight we look at the man
above the strings...
and the woman behind the man.
Raised in Evanston, Illinois,
Malkovich had a lifelong interest
in theater arts...
and as a young man was
one of the founding members...
of Chicago's world-renowned
Steppenwolf Theatre Company.
From there, it was a simple hop, skip
and jump to Broadway accolades...
and Hollywood stardom.
But nothing could prepare the public
for what was to come next.
And so it was that just
eight short months ago...
John Malkovich dropped the bombshell
that sent shock waves...
through the entertainment community.
Turning his back on his
former profession,
Malkovich had to start from scratch...
and pay his dues allover again
as a fledgling puppeteer.
[ Clears Throat ] Hello, ladies
and gentlemen, I'm John Malkovich.
It's-- It's the-- I miss--
I'm really John Malkovich.
[ Giggling ]
[Narrator]
From these inauspicious beginnings...
John Malkovich's rise
to stardom was fast and furious.
His breakout performance occurred
at this year's Emmy Awards--
- [Narration Continues]
- It's really good!
I look really amazing.
I'd fuck me.
If there's anything
that upsets me about it...
it's feeling like
if move into it too quickly...
I'll be, you know, deemed an imitator.
But, um, I think that once
we all get the courage...
to just follow through on
our instincts, like Malkovich has...
I think that, uh, a lot of us
will move into puppetry.
[Narrator]Malkovich's rise to fame
brought about a renaissance
in puppeteering.
No, no, no. What are you doing?
What are you doing?
- I'm making him weep, John.
- You're making him weep,
but you are not weeping.
Don't ever-- [ Beep ]
with your audience.
Until the-- the puppet becomes...
an extension of you, it's a novelty act.
It's, uh--
It's Topo Gigio.
No?
[Man]
He's a technical genius.
He breathes life
into inanimate objects.
It's a very godlike thing...
to be able to take something and,
you know, make it live.
[Narrator]
He was the talk of the town...
from the Beltway to Broadway...
aided in no small part by
his new wife and manager, Maxine Lund.
In Maxine,
Malkovich had found his mentor...
his muse, his inspiration.
In Malkovich,
Maxine had found the love of her life.
- [ Panting ]
- There, there, my dear. Relax.
This travesty will
all be over with by morning.
And the crowds have been
absolutely sensational...
and, um, I'd just like to thank God
for giving us this opportunity...
to share our creative vision.
[Narrator]Nothing was impossible
for John and Maxine in the early days.
Their union was a joyous one,
and together they worked tirelessly...
to further Malkovich's
puppeteering career.
John Malkovich, the artist...
and Maxine, the entrepreneur--
they make this character...
this protean figure
that we cal John Malkovich.
[Narrator]But some say Maxine
has changed since becoming pregnant...
recoiling from the limelight...
and, rumor has it,
from her husband's affections.
[ Whispering ]
I'm so sorry.
[Bing]Malkovich shows us...
a reflection of ourselves,
our frailties...
and our, you know,
desperate humanity.
That's what makes him one of
the most relevant artists of our time.
[Narrator]And what does the future
hold for John Horatio Malkovich?
Well, to quote the Bard,
"He's got the world on a string. "
As the poet said, "The puppeteer's voice
need not merely be the record of man.
It can be one of the pillars,
the props...
to help him endure and prevail,"
and I believe that.
It's over!
Max?
I've gotta head down to A.B.T. now.
I've got the "Swan Lake"
benefit tonight, okay?
But when I come back,
we can maybe celebrate...
Malkovich's big four-four.
Okay? Jesus!
Why couldn't I have found
the portal to a younger body?
What if l--
What if I fall tonight and break my hip?
[Classical]
[Continues]
Like that, little girl?
Huh, lamb?
I love you.
[Applause]
[Man]Bravo!
[Phone Ringing]
Maxine?
[Ringing Continues]
Ma--
Hello? Hello?
- [ Lester ] We have Maxine.
- Oh! My God.
Please, please,
don't hurt her.
Listen, I'll-- I'll give you
anything you want. Please.
You listen to me, asshole.
I don't want your fucking money.
What I want is for you
to leave John Malkovich now!
- Who-- Who is this, Lester?
- Does it matter?
We're gonna kill Maxine
if you don't leave the body immediately!
But l-l-l can't do that.
I mean, if-if I leave Malkovich,
then I'm Craig Schwartz again.
No career, no money.
Maxine will have nothing to do--
She barely has anything
to do with me now.
Jesus, we're going to kill your wife,
you fucking lunatic!
[ Moans ] God.
Listen, Schwartz,
Malkovich is our vessel. We're old.
We're going to die
if we don't get into him by midni--
[Dial Tone Buzzing]
- He called our bluff.
- [People Gasping]
Shit!
Can't we just go inside the portal
and push Craig out?
No, he's much too powerful.
Schwartz would just jam us down
into Malkovich's subconscious.
Lotte.
If I can't have you, no one will.
[Gun Cocks]
-[Lester]Lotte, no!
-[Gunshot]
No, Lotte!
God, no, we can't really kill her!
She's carrying Malkovich's seed!
Our next vessel!
[ Grunts, Shouts ]
Hey! Help me!
Help me!
- Where the fuck am l?
- We 're in Malkovich's subconscious.
The last thing
you'll ever see, Maxine.
- [Gunshot]
- [ Glass Shattering ]
Fag-o-vitch!
[Man]
Johnny, baby, Johnny.
[Boy]
Bad. I am bad. I am bad.
-I am bad. I am bad. I am bad. I am bad.
-[ Groaning ]
I am bad. I am bad.
I am bad.
- I am bad. I am bad.
-[Door Crashes Open]
I am bad.
I am bad. I am bad.
Maxine, lam gonna kill you!
You're creepy.
[ Kids Chanting ]
Little Johnny Malk-o-pee!
Wet his pants so all could see!
[ Both Grunting ]
- I loved you so much!
- [Cars Passing]
Oh! Why did you have
to hurt me like that?
I'm sorry, Lotte.
I guess I loved you, too, in my way.
You are so full of shit, Maxine!
I know.
I know!
It's your baby, okay?
What?
The baby-- it's yours.
It's ours. I got pregnant
when you were in Malkovich.
- You cannot fuck
with me anymore, Maxine!
- I'm not!
I kept it because I knew
you were the father--
the other mother--
whatever--
because l--
because it was yours.
So we're parents?
Together?
Yeah.
Say, uh...
- aren't you John Malkovich?
- No.
- Yeah, you are.
I can't believe
you're in this shithole, man.
- You guys know this is John Malkovich?
- I'm not John Malkovich.
- This is John Malkovich.
- I am not John Malkovich!
[Woman]
Cut it out, you guys.
[ Panting ]
- [ Rings ]
- Yes?
- Lester, please don't do it.
Please don't kill Maxine.
- So you'll leave?
Yes, I said--
I, uh-- I am leaving.
All right. Do it now while
I'm on the phone so I can hear...
and your lovely bride walks.
Uh-- Okay. Okay.
I'm going.
[Loud Whooshing Sound]
Now, my friends.
The time is now.
[ Excited Gasps, Laughing ]
I'm free.
I'm back! I'm--
[ Grunting ]
Aaah!
[ Grunts ]
Lotte.
[Door Slams]
Ooh!
Eh--
Hello.
Hello, young lady.
We're... Malk--
We're Malkovich.
- Hey! Hey!
- [Horn Honks]
Maxine!
I did it, Maxine!
I left Malkovich for you, sweetie!
It's no good being Malkovich
without you.
- It proves I love you!
- [ Lotte ] Fuck off, Craig!
- Doesn't it?
- [ Maxine ] He's not with us.
[ Horn Honks ]
Maxine, I love you!
I'm gonna go right back into Malkovich,
and I'm gonna kick Lester out!
And then you'll love me again!
Maxine!
[Doorbell Ringing]
- Ma-Sheen.
- Hey. Malcatraz.
- Uh, how are you?
- I'm very well. And you?
- Good, good.
- You look well.
- Thankyou.
- How's Celeste?
She's good, yeah.
She's sorry she couldn't make it today.
- She had to go to the store.
- Oh, that's okay.
Charlie, hi!
I didn't even hear the door.
- Lookin' great, Flo.
- I'm looking grateful?
Charlie, we are not
getting any younger.
Well, don't rub it in.
Listen, Charlie,
I know this is going to sound crazy...
but what would you think
if I told you that I'd found a way...
for us to live forever?
All of us.
-Johnny boy, what are you talking about?
-All of us.
Celeste, Floris, you, me.
Gary Sinise maybe.
I don't really understand.
Charlie, this... is Emily.
Isn't she lovely?
[Lotte]
Hey, pass the Cheetos.
- [Maxine] You need more puffs?
- No, I want more.
- Okeydoke. They're covered in grease.
- Shut up.
- Can I swim yet?
- [Maxine]Can you swim yet?
- What time is it?
- Shall we do the cramp test?
Check her.
Let me see.
Are you gonna throw up? Let me see!
Are you gonna throw up?
Are you gonna vomit?
Okay, you can swim.
[Craig]Maxine.
Maxine.
I love you, Maxine.
Oh, look away.
Look away.
Look away. Look away.
[Woman Singing In Icelandic]